Aayush

Category Lead

🛮 aayush4058@gmail.com 📞 8884954783 👂 Bengaluru

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/aayush-sinha-107404115/

Professional Experience

Category Lead - Growth, Unacademy

07/2023 - present | Bengaluru, India

Collaboratively brainstorm strategic projects with cross-functional teams to increase business growth by performing:

- Project Planning: Define project objectives, identify TAM, and allocate resources.
- Cross-functional collaboration: Lead and communicate with cross-functional teams, seeking stakeholder input and support.
- Project Execution: Oversee project execution, monitor progress, and implement corrective actions.
- Risk Management and Issue Resolution: Proactively address risks and escalate critical issues when needed.
- Customer Success & Product Improvement: Helping the UX team to achieve their ticket closure targets by providing resolution to the present learners and improving product features based on user feedback.

Senior Associate - Revenue Growth and Strategy, Unacademy

12/2021 - 06/2023 | Bengaluru, India

- Analyzing business KPIs (Revenue, Lead Flow, Watch time) using Tableau to identify areas of improvement and presenting data to business heads.
- Performing lead segmentation and launching segment-specific revenue triggers.
- Performing planning, budget estimation, and revenue projection for high revenue-generating projects.

Impact and Results:

- 11% increase in revenue by behavioral segmentation and discount sensitivity analysis.
- Saved 21% marketing budget by reducing the spending on lowperforming channels.

Senior Student Success Specialist, Byjus

07/2018 - 09/2021 | Bengaluru, India

Sharing data insights on ticket closure, region-wise escalations, and sales trends using Freshdesk and Leadsquared.

Digital Marketing

Driving CLM campaigns (Email, PN, SMS) for k12 category

Customer Success:

- Interacting with clients and helping in resolving their queries.
- Handling escalated cases (social media and legal escalations)
- Led a team of 7 associates helping them with day-to-day operations.
- Performed market segmentation, cohort identification, and product improvement for "Disney Byjus Early learn" App.

Impact & Results:

- Implemented process changes which reduced the TAT for tech and logistics tickets by **17%**.
- Achieved an NPS score of 8 which was previously 5.

Profile

Business Growth professional with 4+ years of experience in Project Management, business operations, and category management.

Equipped with robust analytical and problem-solving skills and extensive experience in team leadership and operation control, including data analysis.

Education

B.E, Siddaganga Institute of Technology 05/2018 | Bengaluru Electronics and Communications

Skills

MS Excel and Google Sheets

Tableau

Key Account Management & Customer Success

Figma and Canva

Certificates

Foundations of Project Management by Google

∠

Learned about Agile and Waterfall techniques

Agile Project Management Certification by Google ☑ Learned about Scrum and Asana

Agile Virtual Experience Program by JP Morgan Chase & Co. ☑

Intro to Agile, Scrum at JPMC, User Stories, Backlog Refinement, Sprint Reviews

Accenture Project Management Virtual Experience Program on Forage July 2023 ☑

Prepared a proposal for the optimal project management approach

BCG Introduction to Strategy Consulting Virtual Experience Program on Forage March 2023

Conducted market research, consumer needs analysis and to create a client recommendation

BCG Strategy Consulting Job Simulation on Forage - November 2023 ☑

Conducted market research to determine the feasibility of the proposed solution
Communicated a summary of key findings in a clear presentation to stakeholders

Languages

English | Hindi